<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><w:document xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:r="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/relationships" xmlns:v="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:vml" xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main" xmlns:w10="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:word" xmlns:wp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/drawingml/2006/wordprocessingDrawing" xmlns:wps="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordprocessingShape" xmlns:wpg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordprocessingGroup" xmlns:mc="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/markup-compatibility/2006" xmlns:wp14="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordprocessingDrawing" xmlns:w14="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordml" mc:Ignorable="w14 wp14"><w:body><w:p w14:paraId="SW_METATAG_1C74B680_117"><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Normal" /><w:bidi w:val="0" /><w:jc w:val="left" /><w:rPr /></w:pPr><w:r><w:rPr /><w:t xml:space="preserve">Mr. Bean is a British sitcom created by Rowan Atkinson and Richard Curtis, produced by Tiger Aspect and starring Atkinson as the title character. The sitcom consisted of 15 episodes that were co-written by Atkinson alongside Curtis and Robin Driscoll; for the pilot, it was co-written by Ben Elton. The series was originally broadcast on ITV, beginning with the pilot on 1 January 1990[1] and ending with "The Best Bits of Mr. Bean" on 15 December </w:t></w:r><w:bookmarkStart w:name="Bookmark_2" w:id="0" /><w:r><w:rPr /><w:t>1995.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p w14:paraId="SW_METATAG_1D7B1E7A_101"><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Normal" /><w:bidi w:val="0" /><w:jc w:val="left" /><w:rPr /></w:pPr><w:r><w:rPr /><w:t>Based</w:t></w:r><w:bookmarkEnd w:id="0" /><w:r><w:rPr /><w:t xml:space="preserve"> on a character originally developed by Atkinson while he was studying for his master's degree at Oxford University, the series centres on Mr. Bean, described by Atkinson as "a child in a grown man's body", as he solves various problems presented by everyday tasks and often causes disruption in the process.[2] The series has been influenced by physical comedy actors such as Jacques Tati and those from early silent films.[2]</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p w14:paraId="SW_METATAG_714A75A9_184"><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Normal" /><w:bidi w:val="0" /><w:rPr><w:lang w:val="ru-RU" /></w:rPr></w:pPr><w:r><w:rPr /><w:t>During its original five-year run, Mr. Bean met with widespread acclaim and attracted large television audiences. The series was viewed by 18.74 million viewers for the episode "The Trouble with Mr. Bean"[3] and has received a number of international awards, including the Rose d'Or. The series has also been sold in 245 territories worldwide and has inspired an animated spin-off and two theatrical feature-length films along with Atkinson reprising his role as Mr. Bean for a performance at the London 2012 Summer Olympics opening ceremony, television commercials and several sketches for Comic Relief. Besides the acclaim of the show, another reason for the show's appeal in hundreds of territories worldwide is the fact that the show uses very little intelligible dialogue, making it very accessible to people who know little or no English.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:sectPr><w:headerReference w:type="default" r:id="rId2" /><w:footerReference w:type="default" r:id="rId3" /><w:type w:val="nextPage" /><w:pgSz w:w="12240" w:h="15840" /><w:pgMar w:top="1134" w:right="1134" w:bottom="1134" w:left="1134" w:header="0" w:footer="0" w:gutter="0" /><w:pgNumType w:fmt="decimal" /><w:formProt w:val="false" /><w:textDirection w:val="lrTb" /><w:docGrid w:type="default" w:linePitch="100" w:charSpace="0" /></w:sectPr></w:body></w:document>